Sriram Venkitachalam

Digital Strategy | UX Strategy | eCommerce



Consumer insights & data-driven strategy lead with 10+ years of experience in New York, managing teams and leading brands through digital transformation. All-round strategist with extensive experience helming digital marketing, ecommerce, and UX strategy projects, seeking the next challenge.

Summary of Professional Experience

See details on the following pages

| MadeWithLoveInIndia.co.uk | London, UK |
|---------------------------|---------------------|
| Growth (consultant) | June 2020 - Present |

Business Growth & Product Strategy consultant to founder of London-based e-commerce start-up. Driving marketing, customer acquisition, customer experience, and overall product strategy.

| iCrossing, a Hearst company | New York, NY |
|-------------------------------|------------------------|
| Director, Strategy & Planning | June 2014 - April 2019 |

Pitched new business and strategically led accounts through multi-year organic growth. Split time between leading cross-channel digital advertising strategy and experience design UX strategy projects on the agency's biggest accounts, managing a team of account planners, researchers, and content strategists.

Clients: Bayer, Massachusetts Financial Services (MFS), Voya, Bridgestone, TD Bank

| iCrossing, a Hearst company | New York, NY | |
|---|-----------------------|--|
| Associate Director, Strategy & Planning | April 2013 - May 2014 | |

Oversaw digital brand campaigns and performance marketing for online retail client and website redesign UX strategy for financial client.

Clients: Pep Boys, Voya, Alliance Bernstein

Cogito Media - Assistant Director, Mumbai

| iCrossing, a Hearst company | New York, NY | |
|---|-----------------------|--|
| Senior Analyst, Strategy & Planning | Nov 2010 - April 2013 | |
| Drove social media strategy and analytics for retail clients. | | |
| | | |

Early Career Positions

| • | |
|--|---------|
| Crossmedia - Assistant Media Planner, NY | 2009-10 |
| Tata Interactive Systems - Content Developer, Mumbai | 2005 |

Education

MS in Mass Communications 2009 Specialization: Brand Management VCU Brandcenter Virginia Commonwealth University

Bachelor of Mass Media 2005 Specialization: Advertising University of Mumbai

Courses & Certifications

Human Computer Interaction I 2020 Fundamentals & Principles Georgia Institute of Technology edX

Certified Scrum Product Owner 2020 Certified ScrumMaster 2020 ScrumAlliance

Expertise

Digital Campaign Strategy
User Experience Research & Strategy
eCommerce
Social Media Strategy

Creative Briefs

New Business Pitches

Brand Briefs

Qualitative & Quantitative Research

Generative & Evaluative Research

Workshop Moderation

Product Roadmaps

User Personas & Stories

Consumer Journey Maps

Team Leadership

Strategy Staffing Plans

Agile

2006

Professional Experience in Detail

E-commerce Startup — <u>MadeWithLoveInIndia.co.uk</u>

London, UK

Growth (consultant)

June 2020 - Present

Working towards attracting Series A investors, driving rapid growth leading customer acquisition, brand strategy, and customer experience.

iCrossing, a Hearst company

New York, NY

Director, Strategy & Planning

June 2014 - April 2019

Helmed strategy for some of the largest agency accounts advancing multi-year organic growth.

Responsible for managing a strategy team and scoping strategy projects.

Direct Report to SVP Head of Strategy; Direct Reports - Associate Directors, Senior and Content Strategists, Comms Planners

PROJECTS OF NOTE

MFS (Financial Services, Asset Management)

As MFS pivoted to engage the next generation of digitally savvy financial advisors, spearheaded experience strategy for MFS.com.

- Collaborated closely with UI design, project management, content writers, and third-party technology teams in an agile process for the multi-phased, multi-user, multi-region, redesign project.
- Developed user personas, user flows, and collaborated closely with ux and ui designers.
- Developed a digital brand strategy that modernised MFS by bringing its global footprint, culture, and expertise to life.
- Brought domain knowledge of the asset management industry to simplify complex concepts for internal design and content teams

Bayer

Dr. Scholl's

- Led digital strategy during a significant repositioning for the brand that spanned the breadth of the purchase funnel, driving paid social, display advertising, and a new website experience.
- The concerted effort was rewarded with a 10% swing in sales growth and an Effie Silver award.

Alka Seltzer Plus, Coricidin HBP, Afrin

 Transitioning out of a TV-heavy strategy into digital, innovated with short videos and hypertargeted creative to achieve over 200% ROAS on social advertising across the brands over a 3year span.

Voya (Financial Services, Retirement)

As ING rebranded to Voya, oversaw end-to-end experience design strategy, digital advertising, and website content strategy. Grew a \$250K single-discipline account into a \$10M+ revenue-driving, multi-discipline agency account through strategic stewardship.

Brand Campaigns

 Led strategy on the viral campaign, "Born to Save," receiving coverage from 50+ leading national media outlets that drove the Voya brand to its highest peak on Google search trends.

Experience Design

- Leading the website strategy for Voya.com, mined insights through generative & evaluative research, web analytics, and search behaviour.
 Created user personas and user stories that guided the design process.
- Redesign resulted in 3M net-new users within the first year (+70%) and organic bounce rate improvement from 44% to 12%.

Content Programs

 As an always-on strategy to drive relevancy for Voya.com, planned and executed branded content and SEO driven tactics, such as articles, financial tools, and infographics.

Research

- Designed and conducted extensive qualitative and quantitative research program of retirement investors across age groups that formed the foundation of all creative solutions.
- Championed B2B digital transformation roadmap for Voya Investment Management.

iCrossing, a Hearst company New York, NY

Associate Director, Strategy & Planning

April 2013 - May 2014

Oversaw digital brand campaigns and performance marketing for Pep Boys ecommerce and website redesign UX strategy for Alliance Bernstein.

Direct Report to VP Strategy; Direct Reports - Senior Strategists, and Comms Planners.

PROJECTS OF NOTE

Pep Boys (Auto Aftermarket, Retail)

- Focusing on driving e-commerce sales for auto parts & tires and online appointments for service, drove the holistic performance marketing strategy partnering with specialists in SEO, SEM, display media, and social media.
- Developed mid-funnel digital brand campaigns that improved brand perception and drove differentiation for Pep Boys.
- Galvanised growth of e-commerce sales by 250%+ and online appointments by 180%.

AllianceBernstein (Financial Services, Wealth Management)

- Conducted user research and set the vision for the design experience for investors' online account dashboard.
- Collaborated closely with design, content, and tech to see through successful deployment.

iCrossing, a Hearst company

New York, NY

Senior Analyst, Strategy & Planning

Nov 2010 - April 2013

Direct Report to Director of Strategy

PROJECTS OF NOTE

LG Electronics

Humanised and differentiated brand creating a new social media content process unifying disparate creative and community management teams.

Hearst Magazines (Cosmopolitan, Elle, Popular Mechanics)

Developed content strategies to help legacy print magazines catch-up with pure-play digital publishers by tapping consumer interests through their search-intent linguistic keyword analysis.

CVS Pharmacy

Drove email subscriptions for customer loyalty programs, Extracare, BeautyClub, and MinuteClinic, overseeing social media strategy and analytics, and developing lead generation campaigns.

Early Career Positions

Crossmedia - Assistant Media Planner, NY 2009-10

Tata Interactive Systems - Content Writer, Mumbai 2006

Cogito Media - Assistant Director, Mumbai 2005

Education

MS in Mass Communications Specialization: Brand Management 2007-09
VCU Brandcenter

Virginia Commonwealth University

Master of Arts, Part I Specialization: English2006-2007Bachelor of Mass Media Specialization: Advertising2002-05

University of Mumbai